### ABOUT

Research scientist working at the intersection of machine learning and control theory.

Have 10+ years of experience collaborating with small teams to analyze problems, construct solutions, and effectively communicate the results to stakeholders. Excels at synthesizing and distilling complex concepts/scenarios into easily understandable forms and rapidly acquiring new skills and knowledge.

### Work

Yahoo!, Research Scientist, 7/2022 – Present.

- Lead a team of scientists responsible for an optimal budget pacing algorithm for bidding in real-time ad auctions.
- Developed, tested, and launching the following improvements to advertiser ROI:
  - Novel seasonality forecasting algorithm resulting in 10% improvement.
  - Redesigned latency protection system resulting in 20% improvement.
- Rebuilt institutional knowledge of the algorithm's legacy Java code base.

## ACADEMIC HISTORY

University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, Assistant Professor, 8/2016 – 8/2021. Stanford University, Postdoctoral Fellow, 8/2013 – 8/2016. Institute for Advanced Study, Member, 8/2014 – 8/2015.

# ACADEMIC SUMMARY

Published 10 papers (400+ citations) in geometry and probability in top math journals. 20+ keynote speeches at international conferences (e.g. Germany, France, UK).

20+ research lectures at elite universities (e.g. MIT, Columbia, Berkeley, ETH Zürich). Taught dozens of math courses at the upper undergraduate and graduate level.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Chicago, Ph.D., Mathematics, 2013.

National Science Foundation Postdoctoral Research Fellowship

Reed College, B.A., Mathematics, 2007.

Phi Beta Kappa, Barry M. Goldwater Scholarship

### Contact

Webpage: stromborman.github.io Email: stromborman@gmail.com

### CITIZENSHIP USA